Lev Perla

Kazakhstan, Astana Birth date: 11.08.1998

levperla@mail.ru +7 705 340 93 38 in linkedin.com/in/LevPerla github.com/LevPerla

Summary

Experienced Data Analyst with 2+ years of experience who loves to automate processes and find data insights. Confident knowledge of analytical stack (Python, SQL). I combine professional and academic experience that has given me strong research, development, and product presentation skills. Looking for opportunities in role of Data Analyst or Data Scientist.

Professional Experience

Gazprom Neft Apr 2021 - Oct 2022

Data Analyst | Chief Planning Specialist

- Conceptualized and developed a system for assessing the impact of competitors promotions on discount level using Python. Approximately 1 billion transactions were processed. Created weekly and monthly automatic analytical reports for top management meetings.
- Developed a system for optimizing the price of a stele at gasoline stations, considering the company's current strategy, micro and macro factors using Python.
- Conducted research on the price elasticity of demand for petroleum products using regression methods.
- Facilitated business communication with the data science department.
- Administered the department's Jira/Confluence space.

Gazprom Neft Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

Data Scientist | Chief Specialist

Caint Datavalarina Chata I luivanita

Developed the forecasting module as part of the project to forecast wholesale petroleum product prices. Prepared the project for deployment in production using Docker.

Gazprom Neft Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Intern Data Scientist

Developed time series forecasting algorithm using recurrent neural networks on Python and implemented it into existing forecasting system on R language. Managed to increase the quality of the forecasting system by 3% and reduced training time by half.

LTD «TriA», Moscow (Business application development)

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

วกวก

2020

2019

2019

2015

Intern

Developed an optimization algorithm for slicing sandwich panels with minimal residues using Python.

Education

Master, Business Information Analysis Master's dissertation: "Application of recurrent neural networks for financial time series forecasting"	2022
Saint Petersburg State University of Economics Bachelor, Economics, Specialization: Mathematical methods in Economics Graduate thesis: "Development of forecasting price models for wholesale petroleum supplies"	2016 2020
Courses	
 Game Analytics: from basics to advanced strategies (DevToDev) Computer vision course (Deep Learning School, MIPT) 	2022 2021

Achievements

• Winner of GPN Intelligence Cup 2019 in Advanced Analytics (Data science)

Two-week B1 English course (EF International Language Center, Oxford)

• The basics of clean code and agile development in Data Science (Luxoft)

Introduction to Data Science and Machine Learning (Bioinformatics Institute)

• Finalist of the GPN Intelligence Cup 2018 in the direction of "Business and Strategy" (3% of the best solutions)

Core competencies and technologies

- Program Languages: Python (pandas, numpy, sklearn, keras, pytorch, XGBoost), R
- Frameworks/Tools: Git, Docker, Jira, Confluence, Power Bl

Python: Basics and application (Bioinformatics Institute)

- Databases: MS SQL server, PostgreSQL
- Tasks: Machine learning algorithms, Time series forecasting, Computer vision, A/B tests analysis
- Languages: English (Upper-intermediate), Russian (Native)